partsgeek.com 2019-04-17

# Privacy Policy - Partsgeek.com

Privacy is very important to us. Our privacy practices are held to high standards by outside organizations such as TRUSTe. As part of the normal operation of our services we collect and, in some cases, disclose information about you. This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect about you and what may happen to that information. We have prepared a detailed policy because we believe you should know as much as possible about Parts Geek, LLC. The privacy practices of this statement apply only to the partsgeek.com website. Please review the privacy policy of other websites that may be linked to this website as they may have their own privacy policy that differ from our own. 

#### This Privacy Policy tells you:

  * What information we collect
  * How we use that information
  * How we may share that information
  * How we protect your information
  * Your choices regarding your personal information

## Information We Collect

Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and customized experience. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our service to make your experience easier. 

#### Information You Give Us

We receive and may store any information you enter on our website. For example, we collect information from you when you place an order, create an account, call us with a question, write a review, or use any of our services. 

The information we collect from you includes things like: 

  * Your name
  * Your mailing address
  * Your e-mail address
  * Your phone number
  * Your credit card number and other payment information
  * Demographic and lifestyle information, such as personal interests and product preferences

It may also include information you give us about other people, such as the name and address of a gift recipient. 

#### Information From Other Sources

We may also receive information about you from other sources, including third parties that help us update, expand and analyze our records and identify new customers. 

#### Automatic Information

We collect information through cookies and other automated means. Cookies are commonly used by websites to save data on your computer. The information we collect from cookies may include your IP address, browser and device characteristics, referring URLs, and a record of your interactions with our website. We use cookies to create a more personalized shopping experience on our website. 

We automatically track certain information based upon your behavior on our site. We use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior to better understand and serve you and our community. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our site or not), what browser you are using, and your IP address. 

"Cookies" are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing customized services. We also offer certain features that are only available through the use of a "cookie". We use cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Cookies can help us provide information which is targeted to your interests. Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on our site and you may be required to reenter your password more frequently during a session. 

Additionally, you may encounter "cookies" or other similar devices on certain pages of our site that are placed by third parties. For example, if you view a web page created by a vendor, there may be a "cookie" placed within that web page. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties. 

In combination with other information we collect, a cookie may facilitate the tailoring of advertisements and offers to you, sometimes in connection with interest-based advertising. 

To help us understand and enhance our interactions with visitors to our website, we may permit web analytics providers to collect information on our website using automated tools like cookies or web beacons. Web beacons assist in delivering cookies and help us determine whether a web page on the website has been viewed and, if so, how many times. For example, any electronic image on the website, such as an ad banner, can function as a web beacon. We also may share personal information with those providers. 

#### Public Forums

Our website offers publicly accessible social media, blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. 

Under some circumstances we may require some additional financial information, such as, but not limited to: if you are registering using an email account at a free email service, or registering to sell on our site. We use your financial information, including credit card information to verify your name, address, and other information, as well as to bill you for your use of our services. 

If you establish a credit account with us to pay the fees we charge, we collect some additional information, including a billing address, a credit card number and a credit card expiration date and tracking information from checks or money orders. 

## Our Use of Your Information

#### How We Use the Information We Collect

We use the information we collect for things like: 

  * Fulfilling orders and requests for products, services or information
  * Processing returns and exchanges
  * Tracking and confirming online orders
  * Delivering products
  * Marketing and advertising products and services
  * Conducting research and analysis
  * Establishing and managing your accounts with us
  * Communicating things like special events, promotions and surveys
  * Identifying you on our website and tailoring advertisements and offers to you based on your interactions with us online
  * Facilitating interactions with Parts Geek and others, such as enabling you to email a link to a friend
  * Operating, evaluating and improving our business

We use information in the file we maintain about you, and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the website, to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Conditions of Use Agreement. At times, we may look across multiple users to identify problems or resolve disputes, and in particular we may examine your information to identify users using multiple User IDs or aliases. 

You agree that we may use personally identifiable information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze site usage, improve our content and product offerings, and customize our site's content, layout, and services. These uses improve our site and better tailor it to meet your needs. 

You agree that we may use your information to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, are targeted to your interests, such as targeted banner advertisements, administrative notices, product offerings, and communications relevant to your use of the website. By accepting the Conditions of Use Agreement, Legal Notice and Privacy Policy, you expressly agree to receive this information. If you do not wish to receive these communications, we encourage you to opt out of the receipt of certain communications on the notification page. You may make changes to your notification preferences at any time. 

#### Third-Party Service Providers

We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf, such as fulfilling orders, delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, providing search results and links (including paid listings and links), processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions. 

#### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## Our Disclosure of Your Information

#### How We Share the Information We Collect

Parts Geek does not sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties. 

We may share your information with third parties such as vendors and drop shippers to perform services on our behalf such as: 

  * Fulfilling orders
  * Delivering packages
  * Sending Parts Geek marketing communications
  * Conducting research and analysis
  * Processing credit card payments
  * Providing chat functions

Sometimes we may be required to share personal information in response to a regulation, court order or subpoena. We may also share information when we believe it's necessary to comply with the law. We also may share information to respond to a government request or when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of Parts Geek, our customers, or others; to prevent harm or loss; or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual unlawful activity. 

Due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your information that they collect from our website. Therefore, although we use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications will always remain private. 

We may also share personal information in the event of a company sale, merger, acquisition, dissolution or similar event. 

#### How We Protect the Information We Collect

We use reasonable security measures to protect the confidentiality of personal information under our control and appropriately limit access to it. Parts Geek cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. 

We use a variety of information security measures to protect your online transactions with us. The Parts Geek website uses encryption technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), to protect your personal information during data transport. SSL protects information you submit via our website such as ordering information including your name, address and credit card number. 

#### Your Choices Regarding the Information We Collect

  * Stop receiving marketing or promotional e-mails, direct mail, phone and mobile marketing communications
  * Update and correct your personal information
  * Cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services
  * Request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum

To do any of these, let us know by one of these methods: 

  * Follow the directions in a marketing e-mail or direct mail or mobile communication that you receive from us.
  * Open a support ticket with your request using this Link
  * Send a letter with your request and current contact information to: 

Parts Geek, LLC   
777 Route 70 East   
Suite G-103   
Marlton, NJ 08053 

## Legal Requests

Parts Geek, LLC cooperates with law enforcement inquiries, as well as other third parties to enforce laws, such as: intellectual property rights, fraud and other rights. We can (and you authorize us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose us or you to legal liability. Further, we can (and you authorize us to) disclose your User ID, name, street address, city, state, zip code, country, phone number, email, and company name to Parts Geek, LLC participants as we in our sole discretion believe necessary or appropriate in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringement, piracy, or other unlawful activity. 

## Use of Email Tools

You may not use the Email This to a Friend service or other email forwarding services that we offer to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our Conditions of Use Agreement. We do not permanently store the email messages or the email addresses. 

If you send an email using the Email This to a Friend service to an email address that is not registered in our community, we do not use that email address for any purpose other than to send your email. We do not rent or sell these email addresses. We generally discard the email addresses some time after they have been used to send your email. 

## Control of Your Password

You are responsible for all actions taken with your User ID and password, if any, including the payment of fees. Therefore we do not recommend that you disclose your Parts Geek, LLC User ID or password, if any, to any third parties. If you choose to share your User ID and password, if any, or your information with third parties to provide you additional services, you are responsible for all actions taken with your User ID and password, if any, and therefore you should review that third party's privacy policy. If you lose control of your password, if any, you may lose substantial control over your personally identifiable information and may be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. 

## Reviewing and Changing Your Personally Identifiable Information

Following registration, you can review and change the information you submitted during registration including: 

  * Your User ID and email address. If you change your User ID we keep track of your old User ID(s) and your new User ID.
  * Your registration information such as: name, company, address, city, state, zip code, country, primary phone number, secondary phone number, fax number and gender.
  * Your password, if one is required.
  * Your credit card number and expiration date, and other financial information.

You must promptly update your information if it changes. 

Once posted, you cannot change or remove any public postings made in social media or other message areas or the feedback areas. Upon your request, we will deactivate your account, contact information, and financial information from our active databases. To make this request, fill out the support form on our customer service page. Such information will be deactivated as soon as reasonably possible in accordance with our deactivation policy and applicable law. 

We will retain in our files information you have requested to remove in some circumstances, such as to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Conditions of Use Agreement. Further, such prior information is never completely removed from our databases due to technical and legal constraints, including stored "back up" systems. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personally identifiable information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests. 

## Interest-Based Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies to display ads when you visit our website or other sites on the Internet. These companies may collect information about your visits to this and other websites. We may also share personal information with these companies. In either case, the purpose is to provide ads about products and services that may be of interest to you. 

## Protecting Children's Privacy

We are committed to protecting children's privacy on the Internet and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. 

## Links to Other Websites

Our websites link to other websites, many of which have their own privacy policies. Be sure to review the privacy policy on the site you're visiting. 

## Privacy Policy Updates

We may need to update our Privacy Policy as we grow and evolve. If we make significant changes to the Privacy Policy, we'll post a prominent message on our website(s). 

## U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework

Parts Geek complies with the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the European Union. Information regarding the E.U. Safe Harbor Framework can be found at: http://export.gov/safeharbor. 

Parts Geek has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with TRUSTe's program requirements including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe privacy program applies only to information that is collected through this website. 

As part of our participation in the Safe Harbor Framework, Parts Geek uses TRUSTe to resolve disputes relating to our compliance with the Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should first contact Parts Geek as provided below. If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by clicking here. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

## Security

Parts Geek, LLC uses industry standard practices to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal identifiable information, including "firewalls" and Secure Socket Layers. Parts Geek, LLC and treats data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. However, "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet. 

## Notice

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time based on your comments and our need to accurately reflect our data collection and disclosure practices. All changes to this policy are effective after we post the changes to this page. 

## Products

We carry the following: BMW Parts, Mercedes Parts, Volvo Parts, Audi Parts, GM Parts, Ford Parts, Honda Parts, Jaguar Parts, Lexus Parts, Nissan Parts, Porsche Parts, Saab Parts, Volkswagen Parts, performance parts, and accessories for all foreign, domestic, and import vehicles. 

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.
